The solution to this question is ListPreference. When the setting
is tapped, it presents a list of choices as a
dialogue. When a user selects an option, it's saved into
Shared Preferences. Here are the steps to do this. Within
the pref_general.xml file we add a list preference. We give
it a title, and this maps to the string temperature
units. We also need to give it a key for
the shared preferences. And so we specify that to be units.
If there is no value in shared preferences, then it
falls back to a default value of metric. The preference
also wants to know the list of all possible values
here. The two possible values are metric or imperial. So we
pass those in as an array, into entry values. Now
these are just constants for use within the logic of our
app, these are not the user visible strings. So we
need to create entries which is an array of user visible
strings that maps to each one of these possible values. To
have the temperature unit preference show up in the settings activity,
we modify the on create method. We add this line of
code for the temperature units setting. When the user makes a
selection in the dialog, we set the preference summary to be
the new value of either metric or imperial. Here, when we
receive a high and low temperature, we read from shared preferences
to know whether the temperature should be converted to imperial units or
left as metric. Then we return the formatted string for display in
the UI. That completes the code for saving the temperature unit setting.